Let's talk about the time and space complexity of one, the array.
The operation.
Creating an empty array would result in time, complexity, all of one and space complexity of.
This while creating an empty array.
We are creating it just like in time complexity of one.
We are just that making an array.
But in a space complexity at this of and because they're reserved, the space and the memory depends
on the length of the array.
If we have 10 integers, then we should reserve for 10 elements of of integers.
Now, instead of taking a value in array at specific position is time complexity of one and space complexity
of one.
OK.
It's very important.
I think that if we know the specific position, the position of the element that we are going to modify
or insert and then the time complexity will cost of one, because we know the specific position we are
not appending, we are not adding at the end of the array or at the end of the elements, we should
go through all the elements to insert or append elements.
We are inserting a value in an array at specific position or telling, Hey, go to two like element
number 10 and insert a value inside it or update.
This is where it is applicable for updating.
OK.
It is inserting a value in array at specific position time, costing complexity is one of one traversing
a given array traversing means that we are going through all the elements, like printing all the elements
or searching all the elements.
So traversing a given array would result in time, complexity of and and space complexity of one way
of accessing a given cell all of one.
So inserting and accessing a given cell when we know, when we know the cell, when we know a specific
position, when we see and we know the where is the element that we need to insert or excess or update,
then it is a form.
This is the advantage of using IRA.
OK, that way, the space complexity of all operations is of one except creating the empty everyday
because we are reserving the memory, accessing and sir, sorry, accessing a given cell.
We have talked about searching a given value.
Searching a given value is similar to traversing a given array.
So, so searching a given array.
Or it give them value, sorry, it is like traversing a given array it's costing of and in terms of
time complex why this space is often for deleting a given value.
It is a flight in times of in terms of time and space complex.
OK, so we have seen that like searching or traversing.
And going through all the elements will cost time complexity to be more complex in terms of fan while
searching, while sort of deleting, inserting at the given position, deleting from a given position
or given cell or accessing a given cell.
It's sort of fun and this is the advantages of using array.
This is why we use array.
If you have like, you need it in terms of as in the speed terms of inserting, accessing, deleting
for a given array or given value, it's very important to use evidence.